<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Artificial Intelligence on Dr. Lukas Kaupp</title><link>https://kaupp.me/categories/artificial-intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on Dr. Lukas Kaupp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kaupp.me/categories/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts on the late hype around transformer models</title><link>https://kaupp.me/p/research/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/p/research/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kaupp.me/p/research/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Thoughts on the late hype around transformer models" />&lt;p>It seems I&amp;rsquo;m not the only researcher who has doubts about the quality of claims made by late-seen startups. Reasoning /= Transfomer Models. Transformer Models predict the next word(s) according to a certain likelihood. This leads to impressive results in terms of structural integrity but without any claims on information quality. Nowadays if you enter a word in a chat, every phone (the little bar above the keyboard) has the ability to predict the next word (not in the quality of a transformer model) but it&amp;rsquo;s a similar mechanism in its simplest form. You also would not entrust this with reasoning capabilities either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/adnanboz_all-vcs-who-evaluate-generative-ai-companies-activity-7175330977219579904-xy-X?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impact magazine airs article about Context-Aware Fault Diagnosis in Smart Manufacturing</title><link>https://kaupp.me/p/impact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/p/impact/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kaupp.me/p/impact/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Impact magazine airs article about Context-Aware Fault Diagnosis in Smart Manufacturing" />&lt;p>Today, the impact magazine airs an article about my research. The article provides insights into the research that has led to context-aware fault diagnosis in smart manufacturing. Additionally, the article reveals my plans to found a company later this year. If you are a production company with unexpected downtime costs of more than 10 Mio. € we should get in touch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="link" href="https://lnkd.in/e8Wh9fyg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Link&lt;/a> (english version of the article will be available soon)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vortrag IHK Rhein-Main: GenAI - Generative Artificial Intelligence: Text, Bild, Audio - Ein Traum für die Automatisierung?</title><link>https://kaupp.me/p/ihk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/p/ihk/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kaupp.me/p/ihk/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Vortrag IHK Rhein-Main: GenAI - Generative Artificial Intelligence: Text, Bild, Audio - Ein Traum für die Automatisierung?" />&lt;p>Mein heutiger Impulsvortrag als Auftakt im Arbeitskreis Smart Company der IHK war ein voller Erfolg. Ich wurde eingeladen über generative KI zu referieren und bedanke mich bei der IHK Darmstadt Rhein Main Neckar für die Einladung, bei Velina Schmitz und Richard Jordan für die Organisation und bei unserem Host Klaus-Michael Ahrend für die nette Moderation. Für interessierte Leser wird es im Nachgang noch einen Einseiter mit allen wichtigen Informationen geben.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Titel des Vortrags war:
Impulsvortrag: GenAI - Generative Artificial Intelligence: Text, Bild, Audio - Ein Traum für die Automatisierung?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inhalt:
Eine kurze Einführung in die KI und den aktuellen Entwicklungsstand generativer KI in den Bereichen Text, Bild und Audio, einschließlich der wichtigsten KI-Modelle und möglicher Open-Source-Alternativen für unternehmerische Anwendungen, verbunden mit einer kurzen abschließenden Betrachtung der gegenwärtigen Risiken die gesteuert werden sollten. [Link] (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.ihk.de/darmstadt/system/veranstaltungssuche/vstdetail-antrago/5137470/44203?terminId=44203" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.ihk.de/darmstadt/system/veranstaltungssuche/vstdetail-antrago/5137470/44203?terminId=44203&lt;/a>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Successfully defended my PhD thesis</title><link>https://kaupp.me/p/phd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/p/phd/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kaupp.me/p/phd/phd_photo.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Successfully defended my PhD thesis" />&lt;p>Yesterday, I successfully defended my thesis, &amp;ldquo;Context-Aware Fault Diagnosis in Smart Manufacturing&amp;rdquo;. In my thesis, I developed an applied solution to the ever-longing fault diagnosis in smart factories to enable fault tracing and fault origin detection, leading the personnel and maintenance teams to reduce the average 129 mio $ unexpected downtime cost per smart factory per year. To reach my goal, I developed novel pre-processing techniques, advanced AI models, and novel visualization techniques to lead both user groups toward the origin of the fault, which defacto reduces unexpected downtime costs in case of a severe fault.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, only the last formalities have to be carried out before I can call myself officially a Dr. rer. nat. in computer sciences. Here, my Ph.D. journey comes to an end. The journey began back in 2016 and formally started in 2018. In this way, I thank all the great people who crossed my path and shaped the final vision for my thesis. I am grateful for all the support from my employer, the h_da, my supervisors, and my wife. The time that came to an end was challenging and rewarding at the time, but I am also excited because the seed for the upcoming chapter of my life was already planted a year ago. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this plant develops in the future. &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/lukas-kaupp_%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F%3F-%3F%3F-%3F%3F-activity-7136276187055546369-iOux?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>