<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Dr. Lukas Kaupp</title><link>https://kaupp.me/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Dr. Lukas Kaupp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kaupp.me/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://kaupp.me/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/about/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://kaupp.me/about/me.jpg" alt="Featured image of post About" />&lt;p>I am a lecturer, senior research associate, manager of the research center for applied computer science, and research associate for hessian.ai at the Darmstadt University of Applied Sciences. Recently, I received a Ph.D. degree in computer sciences for successfully defending my doctoral thesis about context-aware fault diagnosis in smart manufacturing. My research focuses on AI-based fault diagnosis in cyber-physical systems in Industry 4.0/5.0 smart factories. Moreover, I serve as a reviewer for Big Data Research, IEEE Information Visualisation (also as a PC Member), the International Conference on Industry 4.0 and Smart Manufacturing, and others with my expertise. I contributed international articles and book chapters on artificial intelligence, machine learning, visual analytics, and outlier detection to support the human-in-the-loop in industry-related fault diagnosis. A personal guiding scheme for my research is that a professional is a valuable source of expertise and should be supported to be able to excel in the new processes under Industry 4.0/5.0.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://kaupp.me/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://kaupp.me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://kaupp.me/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kaupp.me/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>